Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
Kimi yo hashire
You must run forth!
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Kyodai na teki o
You must fight the towering foe!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Kimi yo tsukame
You must seize the power!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
A half-century has passed since humanity began moving...
...its burgeoning population into space.
These gigantic space colonies orbiting the Earth...
...became a second home to humanity...
...where people were born and raised...
...and where they died.
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
The cluster of colonies furthest from Earth, known as Side 3...
...proclaimed themselves the Principality of Zeon.
And launched a war of independence against the Earth Federation.
In roughly one month of fighting, the Principality of Zeon...
...and the Federation Forces caused the deaths of half the total population.
Humanity was horrified by its own actions.
Escape From Luna II
Madagascar, locked onto beacon.
Docking speed, maximum minus 2.
Attitude, steady.
Madagascar, entering port.
Docking crews, prepare to secure the ship.
Weapons loaders, on the double!
Recreation services, where are you?
Are you ready to receive our troops?
Pier Number 2, ready!
Secondary combat equipment will be loaded
as soon as Madagascar is docked!
Roger!
We have over 100 civilians with us.
They had no choice but to leave Side 7
when it was attacked.
We'd love to take them if we could.
But the base at Luna II has been in
a constant state of emergency.
We finally arrive at a friendly base
and we can't even rest? How can this be?
I will answer that question.
I'm Wakkein,
Commandant of the Luna II forces.
Are you Bright Noa?
Yes, sir!
The refugees are exhausted.
I'd like to find them somewhere to rest.
We've been pursued by Zeon forces,
so there's been no time for resting.
We cannot accommodate civilians here.
Why not?
All of you, please remain where you are now.
After we consult with
Federation Forces HQ...
...you will be sent to Earth immediately
on a suitable ship.
- To Earth?!
- We want to go back to Side 7!
We will be separating the following
from the regular refugees.
Bright Noa...
Mirai Yashima...
Ryu Jose...
Sayla Mass...
Kai Shiden...
Hayato Kobayashi...
Amuro Ray...
What's your problem? Leave them alone!
Why are you doing this?!
Stop it! Please.
Please give us an explanation, sir!
Cadets and civilians have taken control
of Triple-A classified technology...
...namely, the White Base and the Gundam.
All of you can expect to face
a military court martial.
The White Base shall be seized.
The Gundam shall be secured and
returned to military control.
That is all.
That's not fair!
You haven't even looked into
what happened at Side 7.
How can you say things like that?
Captain. I'm Wakkein,
Commandant of Luna II.
Take care of repairs to the White Base...
...also, the children...
Leave the rest to me, Captain.
You must rest well and recover.
We'll deal with the Guntank
after we secure the Gundam.
What'll we do with it?
It's all in pieces.
Just secure it for now.
Wakkein's pretty strict about his orders.
A Musai will be coming.
I doubt that Char the Red Comet
will give up his pursuit.
If you secure the Gundam now...
You're in no position to dictate our strategy.
You don't know how dangerous
the Red Comet is!
As you're not even a regular soldier,
I can see how you'd feel that way.
However, the Red Comet
is a renowned soldier.
He wouldn't challenge Luna II
with a light cruiser like the Musai...
That would simply be foolish.
Now move it!
You're sure Luna II's radar can't detect us?
Yes. The Minovsky particle density
is a little low, but we should be okay.
It feels strange to be right in front of them,
yet remain undetected.
Now that technology is so advanced...
...we're back to visual-range combat,
just like in the olden days.
Lieutenant Commander,
shall we take out Luna II?
I didn't know you're so bold, Dren.
Luna II has extensive defense facilities.
Your average military strategist would
never expect us to attack with a mere Musai.
And that's why we're going to do it?
I have a plan, Dren.
I'll be looking forward to it, sir.
Could that girl be...
...my long-lost younger sister,
whom I last saw 10 years ago?
No...
She's too strong... to be Artesia.
Drop it!
Move, and I'll shoot!
That's right...
Artesia is much gentler.
We will infiltrate the enemy in normal suits.
What?!
Our first objective...
...is to capture the Federation's mobile suit.
Secondly...
...we are to capture the enemy's new warship,
codenamed Trojan Horse.
We will only destroy them if
we can't capture them. That is all!
Your meals.
Wait!
Take me to Wakkein!
It's a waste of time, Mr. Bright.
But you can't guarantee
that Char won't attack.
I know, but...
In any case, we can't think
on an empty stomach.
You gotta eat when you have the chance.
Or you won't have energy when you need it.
Even if you're just running away.
It's just as Kai Shiden says, Amuro.
Eating meals is like
loading ammo into your gun.
A soldier's gotta eat
even if he doesn't want to.
Shall we go for it, Lt. Commander?
Wait.
Look.
Oh?
This is...
...an infra-red security system.
Deploy mines without triggering the alarm.
Yes, sir.
You just have to remember there are
two settings in the block connection lever.
This is the biggest difference between
the Gundam and Zeon's Zaku.
But what makes the Gundam
so much more superior than the Zaku?
Fighting ability.
Unlike previous Zaku-type mobile suits...
...the Gundam stores combat case studies
in its memory.
It stores case studies?
Does that mean that
the more the Gundam fights...
...the more it learns
and the stronger it becomes?
That's right.
For a complete novice at piloting, like me...
...to be able to fight against
a veteran soldier like Char...
It has less to do with my own skills...
...and more to do with the capabilities
of the Gundam's learning computer.
You're being too humble!
The centrifugal gravity system is out!
Seems like the power generator was hit.
It's Char!
You're saying they snuck in under our radar?
Yes, sir. We believe they're special forces
wearing normal suits.
It's just as Bright said.
Deploy the Magellan!
Mobile Suit
Open this door!
They've probably forgotten all about us.
But at this rate...
Damn it!
Hm? It opened.
What?
I get it! There's no power,
so the electronic lock doesn't work!
Let's go!
Where are Ms. Mirai and Ms. Sayla?
They should be in the room next to us.
Mirai! Sayla!
Bright!
Magellan, emergency launch!
Release the docking locks, fast!
Zeon forces have begun their attack...
...so why haven't you evacuated us
to a safer location?
We have no orders from the Commandant.
Then... Are you telling us
to stay here and die?
N-No, that's not what I'm saying...
Then please contact the Commandant
and do something!
But the Commandant's busy
and doesn't have time to...
What do you think you're doing, you brat?!
Get over here!
We did it!
Gather the crew together.
We're moving the White Base out!
Amuro, release the seals on the Gundam!
Right!
The Magellan is launching.
Let's go.
Damn! It was a trap!
What? The Magellan's blocked the exit?
Start engines! Engineers, on the double!
Ryu! Kai! Amuro!
Have you freed the Gundam?!
No need to yell. We just started.
Sayla, the refugees?
They're moving into the gravity block.
Fraw Bow is directing them.
Good. I'll go check on the Gundam.
Mirai! Once the engines reach critical,
advance the ship slowly!
Yes, sir!
Are you injured, Commandant?
I'm all right. It's just a scratch.
Who's aboard the White Base?
Get this ship alongside!
What are you men doing there?
I thought I made it clear that
the White Base is off-limits!
Only the Gundam can fight against Char!
I order you to leave at once!
I'm prepared to be charged with treason,
Commandant Wakkein.
Is your enemy Zeon?!
Or is it us?
Why you!
I'm not going to lecture you about
the importance of military regulations...
But you must obey the orders you are given!
You go on about military regulations,
but what's the point?
I don't care if soldiers die by those rules.
But isn't it wrong for civilians to lose lives
as a result, Commandant Wakkein?
What?!
Wakkein...
Captain Paolo!
I have something to say, Wakkein...
The White Base, the Gundam,
the Guncannon and Guntank...
... were considered top secret until now...
Yes, sir!
That's why...
It may be unfortunate, but these people are
more adept at using those weapons.
They have experienced two actual battles,
and so we should...
But Captain...?!
That's right. They are essentially amateurs.
As Commandant, you must give them...
...all the support they need to fight.
I'll take responsibility.
I understand, Captain.
I'll do what you say.
Matthew! Fix! Listen carefully...
We enter the port, and take both
the Trojan Horse ship and mobile suit.
Yes, sir!
Roger that!
Let's do it!
It's Char!
Commandant Wakkein.
Unless we get rid of the Magellan...
...the White Base cannot leave port.
At this rate, the Luna II fleet will be
wiped out without a chance to fight.
It's the Musai!
Get rid of the Magellan.
Commandant...
Secure White Base at this position.
All other ships take defensive positions.
Main cannons stand by!
Yes, sir!
Lower the bulkheads!
Aim for the Magellan's
thermonuclear reactor.
All hands, prepare for impact!
Amuro, get away from the passage!
Huh?
Fire!
Char...
Just what kind of man is he?
We did it, Captain!
Commandant.
I think it's best that we leave them alone,
at least until they get to Earth.
Just as Captain Paolo said.
Commandant...
Just as the war with Zeon
gets more and more difficult...
...we keep losing those people
who have much to teach us.
These are cold times to be alive, aren't they.
Captain.
You can rest assured we will deliver
your White Base to Earth.
Father...
Where have you gone?
If a spacecraft relies on gravity alone...
...it will burn up during re-entry
into Earth's atmosphere.
Char chooses that moment
to attack the White Base.
Both sides face tremendous danger.
Will they set foot upon the Earth?
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Re-entry to Earth.
Re-entry to Earth
Next Time
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...